Ye Htet Aung

https://yehtetaung.com

Bangkok, Thailand

Tel: +66 81 516 8397

Email: hey@yehtetaung.com

Github | LinkedIn | LeetCode | Upwork

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Engineer with a six-year background in building business web applications. Specializes in JavaScript, including frameworks like Node.js, Vue.js, and Nuxt.js. A self-motivated and passionate about computer science, also familiar with Ruby on Rails and Python.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer (Remote), BTRS Corporation, Serbia.

September 2023 - March 2024

- Specialized in Cypress end-to-end testing for a QR advertisement application built with React.js, ensuring robust functionality and seamless user experience.
- Communicated and collaborated closely with the CTO on a daily basis to facilitate the creation of pull requests and manage testing development effectively, ensuring alignment with project goals and timelines.
- Technologies used: React.js, Cypress.js. Typescript.

Software Engineer (Remote), Professy Inc., Japan.

March 2021 - September 2023

- Worked with a 6-person development team, focusing on creating and maintaining the company's flagship product, resulting in enhanced product performance and customer satisfaction.
- Built a SaaS application which serves managing subscription services for users using Nuxt.js and TailwindUI. Created
 a complete full-stack workflow using Amazon Elastic Container Service and Docker.
- Contributed to the development of a comprehensive reservation system from scratch, incorporating advanced functionalities and intuitive user interfaces to streamline booking processes and enhance user engagement.
- Technologies used: Nuxt.js, Angular, Coffee Script, Node.js, Express.js, Amazon Simple Storage Service, Amazon Elastic Container Service with Docker containers.

Senior Web Developer, Myanmar Media Linkage Co., Ltd.

July 2020 - January 2021

- Maintained a music streaming web application, ensuring its continuous operation and enhancing user experience.
- Developed and maintained a Node.js API, serving as an essential internal tool for the PHP backend team. It is
 designed to send SMS to the customer of the music streaming web application developed by the PHP backend team.
- Technologies used: Vue.js, Node.js, Express.js, Amazon Simple Storage Service, and Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud.

Junior Web Developer, Myanmar High Society Co.,Ltd.

December 2017 - January 2020

- Contributed to a 6 person development team as a Junior to build an order management project that used data from SalesForce by extracting Excel and PDF files.
- Worked on a web application project as a Node.js backend engineer to coordinate with the mobile development team
 and also lead the frontend team which heavily used the browser's canvas API to create and edit images imported by
 the user.
- Technologies used: Vue.js, Node.js, Express.js, ASP.NET, Angular.

SKILLS

Languages:

Proficient in: JavaScript, and TypeScript. Working knowledge: Ruby, Python, MySQL.

Technologies:

Proficient in: Vue.js, Nuxt.js, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB.

Working knowledge: Vuex, Pinia, React, Next.js, Nuxt.js, Vite, Vitest, Jest, Cypress, Ruby on Rails, ESLint, Babel, Prettier, Git.

EDUCATION

B.C.Sc, Software Engineering, University of Computer Studies, Mandalay.

December 2009 - December 2013

PROJECTS

A Discord bot for forecasting weather

April 2024

- This simple application was built for practicing and showcases best practices in implementing third-party services.
- Built with Node.js.

Path-finding Algorithms Visualizer

March 2024

- This project showcases the execution duration of fundamental computer science algorithms through an aesthetically designed maze user interface.
- It features adjustable execution speed controls to enable users to observe these algorithms in action.
- Built with Next.js, and DaisyUI.

Al Tweets Generator March 2023

- TweetsGen is a dynamic and innovative project designed to simplify and streamline the process of generating tweet ideas effortlessly.
- Built with Nuxt.js, and NaiveUI.

CERTIFICATIONS

Meta Front-end Developer
 2023